



# Nikola Vračević

O Home: 5020, Salzburg, Austria

**Website:** https://vraikonen.github.io

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikola-vracevic-923537155

Date of birth: 13/11/1998 Nationality: Serbian, Croatian

#### **ABOUT ME**

Graduate geodata scientist with a double degree from Erasmus Mundus Coprenicus Master in Digital Earth programme, specializing in Geoinformatics and Earth Observation (University of Salzburg) and GeoData Science (University of South Britanny). With a year and a half of work experience in data engineering, I am interested in software development and machine learning applications, with potentially a broader focus that extends traditional geo-domains.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[ 15/04/2023 - Current ] **Data Engineer** 

Univeristy of Salzburg

City: Salzburg | Country: Austria

Developing a unified geoparsing and data collection pipeline for seven social media platforms, seamlessly integrating an intuitive interface at the Geo-Social Analytics Lab, Department of Geoinformatics with Python and MongoDB.

# [ 01/12/2021 - 31/03/2022 ] **Research assistant intern**

#### Institute of Architecture and Urban&Spatial Planning of Serbia

City: Belgrade | Country: Serbia

Conducting scientific research with quantitative methods and GIS, as well as participating in local and regional planning processes through the development of spatial planning documents.

# [ 30/06/2021 – 30/09/2021 ] Water resources GIS modeler

#### Faculty of Geography, University of Belgrade

City: Belgrade | Country: Serbia

Calculating hydrologic elements using software for the purpose of the Flood risk management plan of Belgrade Region.

[31/01/2021 - 31/05/2021]

# GIS and CAD operator on WebGIS application for local governments

### MapSoft

City: Belgrade | Country: Serbia

Transferring CAD files of Spatial plans' maps to shapefile as well as correcting multiple technical, topological, cartographic and planning errors. Preparing styled spatial database for a server.

[ 30/09/2020 - 31/05/2021 ]

#### **GIS** coordinator

## Faculty of Geography, University of Belgrade

City: Belgrade | Country: Serbia

Responsible for setting the strategy and monitoring the production of evalution maps used on a WebGIS service Geodesign Hub. Developing three scenarios and identifying innovations in energy and transport infrastracture systems.

# EDUCATION AND TRAIN-

[ 01/09/2023 - 30/06/2024 ] Master Informatique parcours GeoData Science

University of South Britanny <a href="https://www.univ-ubs.fr">https://www.univ-ubs.fr</a>

City: Vannes | Country: France |

[ 01/10/2022 - 30/06/2023 ] Master of Science, Geoinformatics and Earth Observation

Univeristy of Salzburg <a href="https://www.plus.ac.at">https://www.plus.ac.at</a>

Address: Kapitelgasse 4/6, 5020, Salzburg, Austria

[ 30/09/2018 - 15/07/2022 ] **Bachelor of Science, Spatial planning** 

University of Belgrade <a href="https://www.bg.ac.rs">https://www.bg.ac.rs</a>

Address: Studentski trg 3/3, 11000, Belgrade, Serbia

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

#### **My Digital Skills**

QGIS/GRASS | ArcGIS Products | Open Source GIS | AutoCAD | Python | R | Java | JavaScript | SQL | NoSQL | Apache Spark

#### **HONOURS AND AWARDS**

20th SuperMap GIS Contest 2021 - Second prize in Mapping category and Third prize

[ 30/11/2021 ] in Application analysis category

Awarding institution: SuperMap Software Co., Ltd

30th International Urban Planners Exhibition - Recognition award in Students'

[ 09/11/2021 ] works category

**Awarding institution:** Serbian Society of Urban Planners

[ 30/11/2020 ] 19th SuperMap GIS Contest 2020 - Challenge prize in Application analysis category A

warding institution: SuperMap Software Co., Ltd

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Serbian

Other language(s):

#### **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

#### German

LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2** 

#### Russian

LISTENING B1 READING B1 WRITING B1

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user